Hey guys, Sean this side. Welcome to
Concept and Coding. And let's just start
without wasting any time.
So, till now we have already seen about
JPQL. Now, let's see about native query.
So, what is native query? Native query
is nothing but a plain SQL queries.
Directly interact with database.
Thus, if in future DB changes,
code changes also required. Means that
since now you are writing a queries
which are DB dependent, right? Direct
plain SQL queries we are writing. So, in
future, let's say you are changing from
MySQL to another DB,
definitely you have to change the
queries, too.
No caching. Now, we are not using JPA
functionality. We are directly writing
plain queries. So, no caching like
persistent context which you were using
like. And also no life cycle management
of an entity happen. So, these are some
of the you can say that points which has
to be considered.
Now, the question might comes to your
mind then, "Hey, then why to use over
JPQL itself?"
So, there are certain requirements like
you have to write more complex queries
which in
like JSONB. Like there are like a JSON
column, right? In your table. And you
have to query that.
Today, JPQL do not support it. You can
access it through native query.
Even though you know that in the JPQL,
everything is related with entity.
Okay? Whatever the columns entity has,
you can have either full entity, let's
say user or user.field1,
user.field2.
But you cannot
expect a result which is not there in an
entity like count asterisk. You have to
fetch it. Can you do with the JPQL? No,
you can't do it.
Or let's say that even if you have to
write a join in which two entities are
not related. Let's say entity one,
entity two. They do not have any
relation one to one, one to many, many
to anything.
So, with the JPQL, which is dependent on
entity, like join is generally
complicate.
Okay? So, with native query, it's like
how you support normally.
Okay? Like you can directly do joining
between unrelated entities also. That is
also possible.
Query efficiency in bulk operation. In
JPQL, what happened is
it entities are managed, right? By
JPA,
its life cycle is also managed, and also
the cache is also updated. So, it has to
keep persistence context updated, which
is your caching, you can say that. L1
caching, right?
So, it's little slower than the native,
which directly works on the DB. So,
native queries are little faster.
So,
depending upon which use case you fall,
you have to go for either JPQL or native
query. But, these are, you can say that,
certain of the advantage and
disadvantages of a native query.
How you can write a native query? Very,
very simple.
You might have seen how we were writing
a query of the JPQL at the rate query
annotation,
right?
Value equals to write a plain SQL query.
Just also add native query equals to
true.
Okay? So, now JPA understand that this
is it has to consider it on a plain SQL
query.
Okay? Everything else is same, like how
what we see in the JPQL.
The same method way, like whatever the
param
you have to provide, it's like this same
only, same like JPQL, no different. Only
thing is just provide native query
equals to true, and now you can use like
a plain query.
One thing, just see here that
select asterisk from This is now not my
entity.
Not my entity, Java entity user detail.
It is is actually table name.
User
this is my table name. Where this is the
field is now actually my DB
field name.
Okay, maybe in the entity I have
something name, but in DB I am saying it
is as a user_name.
So,
in the native query all the things when
you are writing a query, just write from
the DB perspective. Okay, that's the
only one point which you have to
consider.
So, now one question might have come to
our mind by looking at this query. Okay,
like the same JPQL, I have written this
method and I have written above the
query.
When I have written select asterisk,
how it knows that this asterisk should
be like return type of user detail?
Okay, because in JPQL we might have
written you which like all the entity
and it knows that it is an entity, so it
will automatically mapped it.
So,
when all the fields like asterisk is
used,
okay? So, internally does the mapping
between DB column name and entity field
name.
Right? So, whenever asterisk in the
native query asterisk is used, right?
So, whatever the from you are using,
right? In this user detail repository,
it will ultimately do a mapping.
Right? Field by field.
Okay, so uh you will get all the data,
but
what happened when you return the
partial field? So, here if you see, now
I'm returning partial fields.
Select
username
and phone, only two fields.
From user details where name equals to
like this native query equals to true.
Now, how it will do the mapping to this?
Because we know that whenever we are
using an asterisk,
like it will do a mapping with this user
detail itself. But,
what about this? What if I use this only
two fields? Will the JPA will do
mapping?
No. If you start try to test it, you
will get an exception.
Column user ID not found. It will not be
able to map.
Okay?
In case you have only particular fields
to be returned from the native query,
you have to expec- explicitly take care
of doing the mapping.
Okay? So, that is one extra task is
involved.
Now, how we can do the mapping?
There are two ways. One way is using the
SQL result set mapping annotation,
which is used with at the rate name
native query annotation. They both are
used together.
And the second way we I will it's an
object
array that we will see.
So, let's see the first one. Very easy.
Nothing much. Now, let's say that I have
created one DTO.
All the specific fields which I'm
expecting in the user query which is
going to run, I have written it here. I
have a constructor which is accepting
the fields and getter setter for this
one.
Okay?
So, I I I'm expecting only username and
phone. That's all. Only these two fields
I've written in the DTO.
Okay? Now,
in your entity class, in your entity
user detail entity class,
we have to first write native named
named native query. We have already
seen, right? Named query in JPQL, right?
Uh so, there is something called named
native query.
Okay? So, first thing is name. Just
provide any name, whatever you want to
give. Provide a name to your query.
Second is that
write a proper query. Plain SQL. Select
only two fields, one and two. Whatever
the fields you are expecting, write a
proper plain query. Okay? That is the
in the query field. The third one is
result set mapping.
Whatever the result is coming, username
and phone,
it is getting mapped to what? So, now
here
the second thing part comes into the
picture.
SQL result set mapping. So, whatever the
field output is coming from the above
query, we have to now do a mapping and
for that
we are using SQL result set mapping. Its
name is I have given user DTO mapping
and the same name is used here in the
above one.
So, now what happened is here if you see
what ultimately I am doing here is
I told that hey,
whatever the result you are getting,
username and phone,
pass it to the user DTO constructor and
pass it in this sequence.
The username first, second parameter is
phone. My first parameter is username,
second is phone. Okay, in this sequence
it pass.
So, what internally it will do is
whatever the query which you are running
and the result which you are getting,
okay, then it will invoke this mapping
which is annotated with SQL result set
mapping.
Okay, and here with this syntax,
okay, constructor result,
which target class? User DTO class. So,
it will create an object of this.
Okay, and the value it will pass is this
one, username and phone. First parameter
would be username and phone.
So, this is how we are mapping it. And
this named native query and result set
mapping SQL result set mapping is always
used above an entity.
Above let's say I've used our user
detail.
So, now in the user repository, you
don't have to write like above
@query and the full query name. We can
do simply
@query and the name. Whatever the query
name you have to run like we have
already seen previously in the named
query. So, I given this name, run this
query.
And I've told that it's a native query
to true, so expect it to be a native
named native query. Expect it to be a
named native query.
Okay, so I've just given a name. Then
this query will run. It will do a
internally mapping, and this mapping
would be used where it will create an
object of user DTO, and whatever the
field it is coming, it will pass like
this.
So, this is first way of doing a mapping
when you are not returning asterisk, all
the fields.
The second way is manual mapping. Manual
mapping in the sense is that
I am writing the same like SQL query
before. Write our native query equals to
true, so like a plain SQL query, I'm
returning username and phone.
Now here, if you see, I am not returning
user details. I am returning object
array.
So, list of object array. So, list of
object array. List of object array. In
the object array, it's of two size.
First is username \comma} phone.
Then second also is username \comma}
phone, username \comma} phone. Like
this, it will come.
So, in the service class, when you are
invoking the repository this method, you
are getting a output as list of object
array.
You have to do map mapping. So, here I
am doing a mapping. So, I'm using a
stream. Okay. Uh if you don't know about
the stream, at the top I'm sharing the
Java uh stream where I've already
explained it properly. So, check it if
you don't know it. But, this is simple,
right?
All the result which I'm getting,
iterate over it. Okay, now I'm mapping
it. I'm creating an object of user DTO.
First one I am passing as a name, and
second one I'm passing to the this
constructor second parameter like this.
And I am collecting into a list.
Okay, ultimately I'm result uh sending
the list of user DTO.
Because I'm creating an object of user
DTO.
So, this is the way of manual mapping
through object array if you don't want
to use
SQL result set mapping.
But if you have a scenario where you can
directly use asterisk,
then you don't need all this. You can
directly return the entity.
JPA will automatically take care of
mapping the DB column names to a entity
field name.
Okay?
Now, there is one more
advantage of native queries dynamic
native query. In the JPQL, there is
nothing like a dynamic JPQL.
Okay, we will see that. There is a
different name. There is no like dynamic
JPQL. There is a different name criteria
API.
But
there is something called dynamic native
query. How it's used?
In the dynamic native query, now
repository
is not into the picture.
Okay, in the service class itself,
we are using entity manager now.
Okay, now let's say that you have a
scenario that okay, in my where clause,
I have to dynamically put the
conditions. Like let's say if user is
passing name, then only I have to put a
name condition. Name, let's say equals
to whatever user is passing. If user is
not passing name into the parameter, I
don't want to add this also.
So, I don't want to fix my query that
where condition one, condition two,
condition three.
Okay, might be I have in some cases I
have only condition two and three. In
some cases only condition two. Only in
some cases all three.
So, dynamically you have to manage your
query. How you can do that?
So, here in this one, in the service
class, let's say you have this method.
Okay, and let's say whatever you are the
input
fields are coming into the parameter
method parameter.
So, it's a normal string builder. So,
first I'm creating a normal string
builder. Okay, so here if you see new
string builder, I have written a plain
SQL query.
I'm just appending from user details,
like DB query only. I I'm also doing
joining.
I've also appending where one equals to
one. This is just a dummy because I can
add dynamically more query. Let's say if
zero is added, at least I have where
clause present.
So, one equals to one is why you might
be thinking why I'm doing this.
Let's say that if I'm not doing this,
then
you have to be like, "Okay, condition
one I have to add." Then you have to put
like first where.
Okay, with condition one.
Then condition Let's say condition one
is false. It's not even like name is not
there. So, the condition one I don't
have to add. Then you have to always
take care that okay, where is properly
set or not. Okay? And if let's say that
no condition is matched, then okay,
where should not even come.
So, with all this complexity, this
help us, like we where one equals to
one, right? It will automatically save
us from this one.
So, yeah.
So, where one equals to one. Now, all we
have to do is if any more condition
added, so we just do either and or or,
whatever we wanted. Or if no condition
added, then also our query is perfect.
Okay, so one thing is added. Now,
dynamically adding the condition. So,
one thing is let's say that I'm passing
a username just for demo purpose.
Username not equals to null and username
is not empty. Means I want to put the
condition. So, I'm putting appending the
query builder. It's a string, right? So,
I'm just adding and username equals to
question mark.
Okay? So, this question mark later has
to be filled up.
Okay? So, what would be the So, that's
why I'm creating a list of parameters.
List of parameter will store into a
sequence. So, for each question mark
in the list of parameter, I am restoring
that what uh it has to be filled with.
So, parameter.add username, whatever the
username it is coming into this one.
Okay. Now, let's say you have uh like
this if else, you have multiple if else,
so multiple question mark and multiple
value you have to add into that. You
have added into this parameter. You have
done that.
After that, what you have to do is we
have to use an entity manager. Create
native query, and you pass the
stringbuilder.toString.
What it will do is it will give us a
query object. Now, at this point of
time, your string builder
this get converted to this query object.
Which will look like this. Okay? Here,
uh still question mark is not yet
replaced with this your actual values.
Now, you have the query. Now, what is
the second thing we have to do is
execute it.
Okay. So,
before execution, we have to now fill
this question mark.
So, generally, what it does is in this
I'm iterating over the list of this
parameters. Okay? I'm iterating over
this each question mark.
Right? Native query.setParameter.
Okay? Now, what it will do is it will
start Let's say you have three.
In your query, you have three question
marks. So, it's start with like one,
two, three position like this.
So, for each question mark, because uh
for loop is started with zero, because
in the list, whatever the parameter is
starting from zero, right? But, this
question mark internally, it is JPA
concept from like one, two, three.
Okay? So, for each question mark, we
have to put a proper
parameter.
We have to take out from the parameter
list and fill it up.
And now, once your query is properly
built up, all you have to do is
get result list. It will return you a
list of result.
Okay? So, now here if you see that I am
my
output is like specific fields which I'm
querying.
Okay? So, I am accepting into an object
of array.
Now, you can do mapping like okay,
zero would map to this field, one would
be mapped to that field. That upon us.
That we can do the mapping and return
it.
But, the main point here dynamic native
query I want to tell you that you can
even write complex queries which are
dynamic in nature in the where clauses.
So, you can write like this.
But, here
you have to do lot of work.
Okay?
First of all, you are creating a string
builder, then you are creating a
parameter list, right? All then you are
taking the responsibility of replacing
those parameter list into a question
mark, then you are executing it, then
you are doing proper mapping, and then
return it.
So,
that is one thing.
But,
pagination and sorting I will also tell
you in the native SQL in both the
approach with a dynamic or with the
direct at the rate query, that also.
But, I hope dynamic native query is
clear.
How it is actually used.
So, first way in the dynamic I would say
that dynamic native query way. How can
you can use in pagination and sorting?
So, see it's very simple like how we are
writing a plain SQL, the same way we
have to write it. Like nothing no
different syntax we have to remember.
So, I have written a proper query which
I wanted.
All the if else condition I have
dynamically I added it and properly
added into the parameter also in this
list.
Okay? Now, I have to append like a
sorting. Let's say I want to sort order
by. So it's the same query builder. It's
a string only, right?
Query builder. Append
order by like in the same query after
all where clause has been done. After
all where I have to do order by
whatever the append with descending.
It's a normal SQL queries. We are just a
string builder. It's just appending.
Okay, so sorting is done. After that for
pagination in the plain SQL query, what
we have is limit and offset.
So the same thing we have to set like
query builder. Append limit question
mark, offset question mark. Now we have
to put it into a parameter list also.
Parameter. Add size. So this is
ultimately your size.
Okay, like in one page, how many
records? And then offset. Like page
number, page zero, page one, page two,
like so this would be your offset.
Okay, now we get a native query. We just
replace the question mark in the native
query with the values which is present
into this one. Okay.
And then ultimately executed the query.
Okay, so it is as straightforward as it
is. Like nothing.
But if we talk about pagination in the
like how we can do it like if we are
using at the rate query annotation and
native query equals to true. It's the
same way how we were doing in JPQL.
We have a method page pageable
parameter which we can append it. We
don't have to write anywhere here.
Okay, that automatically JPA will
do this for append it for us. Okay. Now
in the just request, we can just send
the page request.of.
Okay, what is the offset page number and
the size of a page?
Okay, and if you have to sort it, you
can like this. We have already discussed
in the JPQL before itself. So it is
same, nothing different.
And if you see the query it will
generate like this. It will
automatically add offset pagination
properly for you.
So, this is one detail like I have a
user details.
Okay, 1 2 7.
And if your query is like
on phone.
So, this 1 2 3 4 5 6 7. So, we are
sorted by
phone
descending. So, 7 6 5 4 3 2 1. And page
zero and five. So, 1 2 3 4 5. So, this
will come 7 6 5 4 3 2 1.
Five in one page.
So,
guys, if you think that I'm going little
fast, it's because we have already
covered most of the things in the
previous videos. So, this pageable and
all we have already seen this query
notation we have already seen. Nothing
much differs than the native query. It's
just like native query equals to true.
Okay. So, it's just like a context like
how it is actually used. Rest everything
is same. Okay. So, if you are finding
the pace little bit fast, it's I would
highly recommend that please watch out
the previous video. That would help you
to set up a context like why it's
linked with the previous video.
Okay. Now, one question to you comes to
your mind, right? Hey, Shash, we have
JPQL.
But I feel that native
query is much more better. Even though
it has a very much DB dependent, but at
least I can write dynamic queries. And
this is something which is very
important in the industry, right?
Because we have everything dynamic which
like no queries is static.
So, then I think JPL JPQL we will never
use it. We will always go with this.
So,
it's there, but with the name criteria
API. Okay, you know that JPQL biggest
advantage is that it is managed by JPA.
And when it And when it is managed by
JPA, you know that there is a framework
which takes care of updating the caching
persistence context and entities
lifecycle. You don't have to worry about
object uh which one is creating, which
one is destroying. So, everything is
properly taken care.
So, with native SQL, everything comes to
your bucket. You have to handle it.
And also, it is DB independent. In
future Once you return, in future you
change from MySQL to something else,
nothing got changed.
Okay?
So, criteria API comes into the picture,
where it supports like the same JPA
enable like JPA manage this.
It works on entity,
not on direct DB. So, it's DB
independent.
Okay? And we can write dynamic
queries
with this.
So, native SQL query support dynamic
query building, but they're database
dependent. That's why JPA criteria API
exists. It is allow you to build dynamic
type safe queries without writing raw
SQL.
Okay, you don't have to write a raw SQL
where you get a chance that you are
you are writing, right? Select asterisk
from If you don't know SQL query, let's
say you mistake with A
you you wanted to write A&D, but you
write AMD.
So, there is like not a type safe, but
here it's a type safe because everything
now we are dealing with object. So,
syntax-wise, it would be like you don't
have to worry about that. Here
everything is a string.
You are putting a string. If there is
some mistake, you won't get it.
So, that's why I'm saying it's a builder
dynamic type safe queries.
Sometimes some engineer feels that
criteria API is very difficult to
understand, but
I feel it easy if you understand it
through hierarchy.
So,
this is the hierarchy which I have
created. This will give you a quick
glance
like
how we can create
criteria APIs
in a very simple manner.
So, the first is criteria builder.
This criteria builder is used to create
everything.
Okay?
So,
first criteria builder
we use to create a criteria query.
This criteria query is nothing but your
actual query which you want to write.
But, here we are not writing direct
string. We are using it through object.
So, in this criteria query, we can do
from, we can do even join. We if we have
to like select only a specific columns,
we can use multi select. If you have to
do all columns, we can use select
method.
We have like a where where you can put
filters. So, filters like condition here
it is defined through predicate.
Okay? You have like and, or, not between
different conditions.
You have order, group by, having. So,
all comes under criteria query. You can
whatever it's required to build a
criteria query.
You will find different method here.
Once the query is created,
okay? Now, criteria builder helps you to
execute it.
So, after that,
once the you got a query, now you have
to execute it. So, here it has something
called type query
object which
executes the above criteria query which
you have created.
So, this type query also has multiple
field like get result list. It will
return you a list of
rows like so it's you will accept like a
list of something.
Get single result only you will get one
object. Let's say user one object.
It also have certain like where you can
put up a generation like things set
first result it's like an offset. Page
number 012
and maximum result
in one page what is the limit.
So if we understand this hierarchy then
it would be very very easy to use
criteria API to write any query.
Okay, let's see one example.
I have created one controller class.
Get user details by phone criteria API.
So
it's a dynamic I'm building like if
phone number comes then only added.
Okay, and whatever the phone number I'm
sending use it. So this is the get API.
Now in the service class if you see what
I am doing is I am using entity manager.
This is my criteria API where I'm doing.
So I've got a phone number.
What is the first step in the criteria
API? We have to create a criteria
builder.
Because from that criteria builder
itself we will be creating a criteria
query and executing that query.
So we use entity manager from that we do
get criteria builder. We get now
criteria builder object.
First step is completed. We created an
object of criteria builder.
Now from this criteria builder we have
the second step is to create a criteria
query.
Okay, this is the second step like we
have to create a criteria query.
So now from the criteria builder I am
creating a criteria query. Okay, now
what is this internally?
Internally
what my each row looks like.
That we can tell. Let's say that if you
have
a query where you are doing a stress,
means all the objects, all the objects.
All the fields of a particular entity.
Okay, then you can do user
details.class.
If you have like a specific field like
field one \comma} field two \comma}
field three, then you can use object
array.
Okay?
So, whatever
your each row looks like
you can add it here.
Okay, so currently my here in this demo
I'm using select a stress for now. So,
for a stress is like
since this we is we are talking about
entity, so all entity you
it's let's say user detail entity.
So, each row is my user detail.
Okay? So, now I have created the
criteria query.
Now from this criteria query I have
actually have to create everything.
Let's say select
from
where
order by having.
So, that I have to do.
So, from this criteria query I am doing
first like from
which table. So, table name we have to
give right? From which table it has to
fetch the record. So, from
this table I have to fetch the record.
Okay? So, now
the first table. So, it is possible
right? From table one join let's say
table two. So, this table one which is
first one right? It is always known as
root.
The first one is also always known as
Okay? So, now I have added the from
clause.
It is here in the root.
Now
I have to also like select either one
row or multiple rows whatever. So, I am
using criteria query, the same query.
select
user.
Okay?
Select all the fields of this table.
Okay? So, first I told you, right? This
user represent the first table.
So, criteria query.select. If you have a
specific fields, you can do criteria
query.multiselect.
And whatever the fields, like
user.field1,
\comma} user.field2, like this.
But here I want all the fields, that's
why I put user and I've used select,
which is equivalent to select asterisk.
So, okay, I have done this. I have done
this from. Now, I have to use where. So,
criteria query.where. Now, I'm adding a
where clause. Now, in this where clause,
I have to add condition.
So, condition is here predicate. So, now
I am creating a predicate.
So, predicate is created here is like
criteria builder. Criteria builder helps
in creating a predicate. Criteria
builder.equals.
There are multiple methods. I will tell
you.
So, I want to like phone number equals
to whatever the phone number is coming.
You can make it dynamic, like if
phone number is present, then only do
this. Otherwise, don't do it.
Okay?
So,
currently I am just writing like
criteria builder.equals
whatever the field name in the table you
have. So, my this table, user table,
like the first root table, user.get.
This is the field. Okay? This is your
entity field name, not table DB column
name, entity field name. Maybe in DB it
is known as phone underscore number, but
actually in entity Java it is known as
phone.
Okay? So, I'm using that name.
So, this object user.getphone,
\comma} phone number which is coming
from the input parameter.
So,
criteria builder.equal. So, it is like a
condition. It is making like
phone equals to the phone number which
is coming.
It is creating a condition.
And I'm using that condition and putting
into this via clause.
So, with this I have also created a via
clause.
I don't want order by having and all.
So, now I my
criteria is done. So, I am
using an entity manager create query.
Now, I am creating a
query out of it. Type query.
Okay? So, I'm creating a type query out
of it. Whatever the
criteria query comes,
I generated a query type query out of it
which can be now executed.
So, here JPA might have done
some mapping or you can say that some
translation what we have written and it
gives us a type query.
Now, this query directly can be written
run I run get result list. Means return
me more than what this query can return
more than one row. So, that's why I use
this and accept it into a list and
return.
So, that one is clear.
Okay. So, just see this example.
I have like select this from user
details.
So, these are the data present into
currently my DB. 120 120 110.
Three records. 1 2 3. Okay.
I am trying to hit a get API.
Phone number I am passing is 120 in the
controller.
120 I am passing and the same 120 goes
here.
So, ultimately it it should do phone
number equals to this one.
So, I should only get the list of output
where phone number matches to 120. So,
here I will get only this two where 120
matches.
Okay? And if you see the query, it is
select kind of an asterisk, all the
fields, from this is all my root, where
clause, this is the predicate, and which
is
get it
there.
Okay? So, one question comes to my mind,
right? Okay, in this predicate
generation, cb.equals,
what are different things we can do? So,
here if you see, these all things we can
do.
cb.equal,
like whatever the field from the table
you want,
then the value.
Okay? So, generally any condition is
like
field equals to something, 1 2 3,
field like So, this is the first field
name, right? So, and the field name is
from your root or table.
So,
it is check for equality where phone
equals to 123. This is your condition.
Then you have cb.not equal,
field and the value, it would be like
phone not equals to 123.
Then cb.gt, which is greater than,
like field and the value, phone greater
than,
greater than equals to, lt, less than,
less than equals to. So, these are there
in the comparison operator.
Okay?
Then we have logical operator.
Logical operator means like cb.and,
so like
you have something like condition one
and condition two.
So, it also has this, criteria
builder.and, predicate one, \comma}
predicate two, condition one, \comma}
condition two.
So, like phone equals to 123
and name is like
something like this SJ.
So you have this is my condition
predicate one. This is my predicate two
and we are now just you combining it.
Similarly CB.or, CB.not. It's not
negation.
So here if you see, I am creating
predicate one.
Criteria builder.equals phone this one.
So it is one condition. I am creating
another condition criteria builder not
equals name AA. This is second. I have
to now club it.
So CB.and
I club it and it will become my this
predicate.
And then I use put it into the where
clause.
Similarly string operations you have
like CB.like also you have. This one you
can use it like field name and
how you wanted it.
CB.not like
So it's all very straightforward like
this guy has all the possible where
things which we can have like it has
that.
Like CB.in, CB.not
Okay. So in it's a collection, right?
CB.in user that get phone
like
in you will have like what all the
possible values it can come here. So
value.11.7.
You can put anything.
Okay?
So similarly like you can use it not in.
So here I will show you one example how
to do select multiple fields.
Okay, I till now I have shown you like
select asterisk one but for the same
criteria API
you can do this. So first step we know
we have to create a criteria builder
object because this is ultimately used
to
be
used to create everything.
So criteria builder I used it to create
a criteria query but here
this one is like what each row would
look like. So my each row would look
like object array because field one
\comma} field two \comma} field three.
It could be a string, it could be long,
it could be int, something.
So, it's object array.
Then, so this my second part is done.
Then, the third one is like from
my table one. Table one is known as root
generally here. So, root
whatever the table one. So, criteria
query \dot} from, this is my
table.
Then, I have to putting a select
like whatever all the fields. So, here I
am using now criteria query multi-select
because I can have not extras, I can
have multiple fields. So, from this
table user, I can have like whatever the
fields I wanted to fetch.
Then, I created a predicate, which is
nothing but a condition and I put into
the where clause.
I created a type query out of this
entity manager, pass this query and run
it.
Now, output would look like object array
because this is what I told. My each row
would look like this. So, and result
list will return the list
not one. So, list of
each row would look like this. And I'm
doing a mapping in the user DTO.
Like object array
first is a string, second is phone and
in the new DTO pass like this
and return it.
Very simple.
Okay?
And it is also possible to do joining
also. So, nothing much differ. So, here
if you see, we have like from table one
then you have like join
whether inner join, left join, table
two.
Okay? And here in this we don't need on
and something because we it is like a
JPQL, it is on entity. So, it knows that
this entity is related with this column.
So, the same thing. I created a criteria
builder.
I created a criteria query out of this
criteria builder and each row is looks
like this because multi select I might
be doing it.
My table one from clause is this user
details. So and the first table is known
as root here.
So this is my first table.
Now I am joining my first table dot
join. What type of join? Join type is
inner. Either here you can have also
write left right right join.
And which table you want to join? User
address. So here again
if you open the user detail
entity class
Okay, there would be like at the rate
one to one mapping and the field user
address is the another entity.
There whatever the field name I have
right, I use that only. I am not using
the table name of that user address.
Okay, entity has a relationship. So this
is the field name in the user details
one to one mapping.
Okay, so this root table first table dot
join
with this user address I want to do
inner join.
So it will
like this it will come. Join your table
one and this would be considered your
table two generally. Means or I would
say that since we are talking entity one
entity two.
Okay.
So now
from is done this join query is done.
Now we have to do select. Now I have to
do multiple right? Each row is look like
object array so multiple select.
Criteria query dot multi select.
So one field I want from user root
table. User dot get name.
Second from the let's say from address
table I want this city only. So this is
my represent like a second entity join
second table. So address dot get city.
Then it's a predicate condition you
added. You create a type query run it.
Since it's an object array you have to
do a mapping and return it.
That's all.
Okay, so this is as simple as it is.
And paginations and sortings is also
very much
but not that complicate but here one
thing is like we all have to add it like
in the hierarchy if you see
we have to use this
methods to for the paginations.
So here if you see this is how you can
do.
Criteria builder object, I created a
criteria query. Now I am want select
asterisk. Each row is my complete
details.
Okay, so user details
I have added from clause. There is no
join. I put select asterisk. All columns
of user details select is like all
column of this.
Predicate, this is my condition where
clause I have added into that. Now after
this where clause I need to do sortings.
Okay, so criteria query also has order
by.
So order by
now
you have to like
which field.
Okay, so whether descending this field
should be descending increasing
whatever. So you can find a field name
like this user.get
root right user.get whatever the field.
And criteria builder offers like dot
descending dot increasing. So you can
use that order by name descending it
will translate to this.
And for paginations, once you get the
type query now type query has this two
method.
Set first result which is kind of an
offset page number maximum result
what is each page going to look like and
ultimate run it.
So if you understand that hierarchy
right criteria query is very simple
right? All is like methods we have to
end with.
Okay, so if you see this like exactly
same
descending order and five.
Like one page is five. I'm sending page
zero five.